Brandon Franklin

Boca Raton, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

Objective:

Curate robust web applications utilizing the latest technologies and adhering to the highest of standards. Experienced with stages of web development including design concept and prototyping, QA, deployment, release and maintenance. Strong background in design theory and effectively communicating between all teams involved in software development lifecycle.

Education:

Graduated 2011: Bachelors of Graphic Design, Digital Media Arts College, Boca Raton, FL

- Delta Epsilon Iota Honor Society

Work Experience:

Cendyn

Lead Front End Developer, January 2019 - Present

- Conceptualize, prototype and build product features that integrate with legacy and modern technologies
- Work with other team leaders to determine tech stacks for new product development
- Update and maintain product integrity through ongoing enhancements
- Conduct code reviews for internal and offshore teams
- Create and update documentation for best practices, component usage and API consumption using the latest features in JavaScript

Front End Developer, February 2016 - January 2019

- Collaborate with both UX Designers and Back End Developers
- Prototype and rapidly iterate to test assumptions for product features
- Aid QA team in exploratory testing and business related defects
- Create, implement and maintain living UI kit

Production Manager, May 2015 – February 2016

- Implement, train and maintain industry best practices for CSS and HTML
- Monitored the status of each project and worked to ensure goals were met by the production team
- Proactively identified potential production challenges and provided solutions to prevent in the future
- Ensured proper communication between internal departments, Managers, and Customers
- Organized alerts and scheduled jobs for server maintenance, data processing, and deployments

Product Services Manager, July 2013 – May 2015

- Daily client interaction with Fortune 500 clients Starwood Hotels, Hilton Worldwide, Hyatt Hotels & Resort, IHG & Four Seasons Hotels, and many more
- Close interaction with advertising, design, sales, and programming teams to ensure cross departmental synchronization of projects and product launches

Production Coordinator, July 2012 - July 2013

 Expedite day to day operations by streamlining workflow and delegating tasks to suit team member strengths

Web Production Specialist, July 2011 - July 2012

- Build website templates for Fortune 500 clients

Brandon Franklin

Boca Raton, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

UserSight

Web Design Associate, January 2011 – July 2011

- Create and maintain several custom websites for local South Florida businesses
- Comprehensive knowledge of 960.gs, color theory, composition, and typographical elements
- Monitor uptime for websites as well as identify, diagnose, troubleshoot issues, and implement solutions

Projects:

Sales Suite Product Redesign (Active)

- Responsible for leading a team of other department leads through the ideation, iteration, validation, prototyping and testing of concepts for the redesign of our flagship product.
- Directly influence tech stack and product design decisions for a maintainable and scalable environment.

Living UI Kit (Active)

- Worked with the UX Design team to cultivate a philosophy for rebranding the entire suite of 22 products.
 This involved conceptualization and prototyping items to include in the kit.
 - o Implementation
 - O Testing
 - O How to use tutorial
 - O Updates and maintenance of code base

Hilton Worldwide Product Suite (Completed)

Responsible for the recruitment, training, and development of 4 new team members in an effort to
increase productivity by the end of the year. The team was able to exceed expectations two-fold and
deliver the final release of the project early and under budget.

Skills:

Proficiencies

HTML5, CSS3, LESS/SASS Preprocessing, Bootstrap 3 and 4, JavaScript, Vue, Vuex, jQuery, Version Control (TFS, GIT, SVN), Responsive Web Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Adobe Creative Suite, Windows/MAC, VS Code, Working with Offshore/Remote Teams

<u>Familiarizations</u>

Angular 1x, React, Nuxt, ES6, TypeScript, MVC, ASP.NET, .NET Core, API Creation, Node, NPM, Yarn, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, Lean UX, Asynchronous Programming, Unit Testing

Achievements & Interests:

Eagle Scout
BocaJS Meetup
Github open source contributor